<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-02-16T15:20:47+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Anne Lee Steele</title><subtitle>Website for Anne Lee Steele</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Publication: Notes on the (American) Empire</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/field-notes/on-protests-revolutions-and-empire-notes-on-end/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Publication: Notes on the (American) Empire" /><published>2020-03-09T23:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-09T23:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/field-notes/on-protests-revolutions-and-empire-notes-on-end</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/field-notes/on-protests-revolutions-and-empire-notes-on-end/">&lt;p&gt;Dear all,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently published a piece for The Graduate Press, a student-run publication here at The Graduate Institute, titled “On Protests, Revolutions, and Empire: Notes on America”. This was for their Spring 2020 REVOLUTION issue. &lt;a href=&quot;https://thegraduatepress.files.wordpress.com/2020/03/tpg-publication-final.pdf&quot;&gt;You can download a copy of the issue here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dear all,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Impressions: On Mountains, Panels, and Fondue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/field-notes/geneva-first-field-notes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Impressions: On Mountains, Panels, and Fondue" /><published>2019-12-09T23:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-09T23:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/field-notes/geneva-first-field-notes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/field-notes/geneva-first-field-notes/">&lt;p&gt;Dear all,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a few months since I’ve arrived in Geneva. This is a fascinating place (though not without its challenges, of course), and I’m finally starting to feel settled. There’s a lot to share, and that will take time to process, but I wanted to post a few photos of the past few months. I’ve been getting lots of mountain time, overdosing on politics, and studying up on just about everything. More on that later; but in a meantime, a few photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A view from my flat:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582666518/room_with_a_view_gwikrm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;geneva&quot; title=&quot;geneva&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking back from the crag:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582666548/climbing_b0ljni.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Young climate protests at the Global Climate Strike, which happened to be on the same day as the Free Tibet protests:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582666597/climate_i1qw5n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582666654/tibet_lila7j.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Views of the Matterhorn:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582666677/mountain_j2kowj.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fondue at one of my favorite places in Geneva (Bains des Pâquis):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582666871/fondue_z5gj9f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many, many forums: on climate justice, on human-centred design, on Brazil’s politique, on jewel auctions, and everything in between…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582668184/auction_pyabm6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582666726/protest_1_j35xs4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582668298/todo_bien_fs4te1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, a photo of beautiful Lake Geneva at dusk:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582668146/lake_geneva_night_tecm6v.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure: I post more frequently on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/anneleesteele/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;; but will be returning to longform and this blog soon. I may be posting the cycling stories I’d compiled from last summer here as well, for posterity’s sake. Until soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dear all,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Greetings from Geneva– I’m bringing back the blog!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/field-notes/greetings-from-geneva-bringing-back-the-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Greetings from Geneva-- I'm bringing back the blog!" /><published>2019-09-17T23:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-09-17T23:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/field-notes/greetings-from-geneva-bringing-back-the-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/field-notes/greetings-from-geneva-bringing-back-the-blog/">&lt;p&gt;Dear all,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work and life has meant that I’ve been constantly on the move for the past few months (in all honesty- for the past few years is probably more realistic): somewhere between Kathmandu, Washington DC, and Bristol. It feels good to be living somewhere long(er) term, and I’m excited to be based in Geneva.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being stationary usually means that there’s time to reflect and digest. For the past few months, I’ve had the opportunity to go through arsenals of old photographs, writings, field notes and emails. While some of that has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/mmntsbyanne/&quot;&gt;posted here&lt;/a&gt;, I thought it might be nice to have my own space (as separate from a social network).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be a place to post thoughts, reflections, and adventures (both physical and intellectual). I hope that I’ll be able to back-post some old writings, specifically letters and photographs that were sent when I was more mobile than not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must admit: blogs have always felt a little weird for me. I mean, why would anyone be interested in anything I have to say? Why take the things that I fiercely protect as private thoughts, and put them into a public space? Especially a ‘public space’ like the internet, where I’m inevitably bound to get myself in trouble? Is it narcissism? Post-teenage angst? A combination of all of the above, perhaps?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to think that this place will be a bit more than that. First and foremost, I’d like this blog to be for those that were too far away to know what I was up to at the time, and well as for anyone that happens to be interested in what I’m up to these days. Perhaps more selfishly: this blog will also be for myself, a way of keeping myself accountable to writing, publishing, and digesting the world as my lens evolves. Finally, this is my small attempt at control over my digital half life, and over the parts of myself that are shared online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll inevitably make mistakes, but I might as well try. Let’s see what happens!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anne&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dear all,</summary></entry></feed>