<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-13T15:36:15+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Anne Lee Steele</title><subtitle>Website for Anne Lee Steele</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Thinking and Writing about ‘Open’-ness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/field-notes/open-thinking-open-writing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thinking and Writing about 'Open'-ness" /><published>2021-01-17T21:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-17T21:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/field-notes/open-thinking-open-writing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/field-notes/open-thinking-open-writing/">&lt;p&gt;Dear all,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much for using this blog! Sorry about the long break. Between graduate school and the pandemic, I’ve been struggling to keep up with writing regularly for anything not directly related to work and research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funny thing about having a blog during times of Twitter, Instagram, Medium, Substack, and TinyLetter is that blogging feels distinctly like speaking into the abyss. What role do they play these days? There’s no ready-set audience, no possibility of payment, no algorithmic recommendation system. There’s no comment section for feedback. No google ad-words. Just me and my lonely CMS, writing into/at the digital abyss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, there’s something that I really like about this space. It feels like my own little patch of the world wide web. I guess in a lot of ways, it feels like a &lt;a href=&quot;https://tomcritchlow.com/2019/02/17/building-digital-garden/&quot;&gt;digital garden&lt;/a&gt;, something that I own in a digital world populated by proprietary platforms. I’m currently building one for thoughts that aren’t blog-worthy, to do &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethnographymatters.net/blog/2012/08/02/writing-live-fieldnotes-towards-a-more-open-ethnography/&quot;&gt;open ethnography&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ethnography.com/2012/08/this-week-in-ethnography-writing-live-fieldnotes-with-social-media-towards-a-more-open-ethnography-ethnography-matters/&quot;&gt;live fieldnotes&lt;/a&gt; for anyone who might be interested (stay tuned!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about this “open” approach to writing. From where I stand, it has three problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-first-is-an-obvious-one-why-do-these-musings-have-to-be-public-in-the-first-place&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first is an obvious one – why do these musings have to be public in the first place?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I struggle with this one the most. When listening to a podcast about &lt;a href=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/ca/podcast/c-besteman-h-gusterson-life-by-algorithms-how-roboprocesses/id425683368?i=1000488461179&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Life by Algorithms&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; a new book by C. Besteman and H. Gusterson, the authors were pretty bleak. “The age of privacy is over,” they said. Does this mean that the age of private thoughts or private acts are over, too? Do the photos that I took of my grandmother mean anything, when I don’t share them with her? Or with anyone else at all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pressure to join social platforms and to live in a public way is itself well-documented. Because the majority of &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;social and public life is now on proprietary platforms&lt;/a&gt;, especially during the pandemic, and because influencers have shown time and time again how &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/what-is-an-influencer/&quot;&gt;fame on the internet can lead lead to fame in real life&lt;/a&gt;, more than ever, sharing our lives in public feels like a way of manifesting social connections. Recording our lives seems like a way of connecting with strangers and friends in real time, or perhaps even creating new income streams and economic opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the hope that this perspective brings, I can’t stop thinking about this by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentjournal.com/author/caroline-busta/&quot; title=&quot;Posts by Caroline Busta&quot;&gt;Caroline Busta&lt;/a&gt;. She writes about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentjournal.com/2021/01/the-internet-didnt-kill-counterculture-you-just-wont-find-it-on-instagram/&quot;&gt;what counterculture looks like in the age of the internet&lt;/a&gt;, and how we’re more likely to see countercultural work as anonymous and local rather than anything done in public, let alone on social media. Because all aspects of our social lives are intrinsically tied to an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2019/nov/22/attention-economy-in-hyperdrive-how-tech-shaped-2010s-oliver-burkeman&quot;&gt;attention economy&lt;/a&gt;, one where a few dominant for-profit platforms benefit off of both the critics and the consumers, would keeping my thoughts to myself be the most effective (and least-destructive) way to reflect? Are there alternatives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leads to my second set of critiques, because this kind of privacy is often associated with secrecy. In an era of transparency and &lt;a href=&quot;https://opendefinition.org/&quot;&gt;open knowledge&lt;/a&gt;, not-sharing has a distinctly negative connotation. Despite increasing calls for data privacy and protection, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2015/06/10/in-the-information-debate-openness-and-privacy-are-the-same-thing/&quot;&gt;which are usually looked at in direct opposition to “open” ethics,&lt;/a&gt; I usually tend to get a little stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-thoughts-made-out-in-the-open-actually-makes-us-more-accountable-to-them-does-it-actually-facilitate-rigorous-thought-transparency-does-it-have-any-positive-effects-at-all&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do thoughts made out in the open actually makes us more accountable to them? Does it actually facilitate rigorous thought? Transparency? Does it have any positive effects at all?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discussions about the effects of openness are usually transposed upon the open data movement, which began in the 2000s as a means to help make governments and organizations more transparent and accountable. I recently wrote an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.graduateinstitute.ch/communications/news/open-movement-and-its-discontents&quot;&gt;op-ed for the Graduate Institute communications team&lt;/a&gt; about this, and how it has created an uneven landscape: where some have enacted radically open and accountable policies, while others have remains almost entirely unaccountable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The open ethic has also turned into &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbestechcouncil/2018/07/16/how-open-source-became-the-default-business-model-for-software/&quot;&gt;an effective business model, especially in the world of software&lt;/a&gt;, where volunteers and other contributors have been able to build upon proprietary software and iterate coding ideas and resources countless times. This is part the reason why we’ve seen such an explosion in the space, but also what’s now creating problems about &lt;a href=&quot;https://nadiaeghbal.com/oss/&quot;&gt;who maintains what’s now become the internet’s informational infrastructure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when I expand outside of these two applications, I’m caught in a catch-22. While anthropologists &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/17/opinion/sunday/morozov-open-and-closed.html&quot;&gt;and many others&lt;/a&gt; have written extensively about the tensions behind the ‘open’ and ‘transparent’ ethic, many others have been actively working on solutions to this problem (and ironically – aren’t usually as visible as the former), &lt;a href=&quot;https://fellows.frictionlessdata.io/blog/anne-goodtables-blog/&quot;&gt;something that I wrote about in on the Frictionless Fellows blog&lt;/a&gt;. These critiques, that ‘openness’ can disguise power in different different ways, are absolutely valid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, I’m not sure what role free labor plays within all of this. While the open source software movement is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/43zak3/the-internet-was-built-on-the-free-labor-of-open-source-developers-is-that-sustainable&quot;&gt;confronting the difficulty of this business model&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/43zak3/the-internet-was-built-on-the-free-labor-of-open-source-developers-is-that-sustainable&quot;&gt;the foundation it set for the movement&lt;/a&gt;, the wider sphere of “open” data projects is largely funded by the public sector, not private. On the other hand, the “open economy” of the gig workers is largely associated with precarity. Where do I place myself in all of this, when unpaid writing is more common than ever, and while paid writing adds boundaries to who can access it? How do I balance the unpaid labor that “pure” open-ness seems to require, without falling into the kind of precarity that it ultimately seems to lead to on an individual level?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, there is so much I have learned from open resources, and the people that put their thoughts out into the open. I can’t tell you the number of times I have stumbled upon Twitter accounts or personal blogs where the open and honest writing of their authors has informed my own thought process and point of view. has been deeply informative. These resources encouraged me to&lt;a href=&quot;http://open-source-social-science.github.io/&quot;&gt; compile my own list&lt;/a&gt; of resources for people to use, and hopefully give back to the plethora of free and open knowledge that I’ve definitely been able to benefit from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe this is where my latent idealism seeps back into my point of view. Despite all its faults, we have never existed in a better time to actually engage with different publics on the internet, and experiment with new ways of collectivising people online and in real life. Yes, the fear of replicating your own world view (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/False_consensus_effect&quot;&gt;false consensus&lt;/a&gt;) or of having friends that are exactly like yourself (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/archive/politics/2006/10/16/why-everyone-you-know-thinks-the-same-as-you/0560e849-925e-42ca-a786-861d93db3dfa/&quot;&gt;homophily&lt;/a&gt;) is very real, but if we can find better ways to negotiate difference, maybe the “open” ethic can help us to bridge the gap between public trust and interpersonal accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-leads-to-my-final-set-of-questions-how-do-balance-the-positive-aspects-of-the-open-ethic-alongside-the-negative-impacts-of-proprietary-platforms&quot;&gt;This leads to my final set of questions. &lt;strong&gt;How do balance the positive aspects of the open ethic, alongside the negative impacts of proprietary platforms?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something I’m interested in understanding, so I don’t really have any answers as it currently stands. On the social network side of things, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/the-decentralized-internet-is-here-with-some-glitches/&quot;&gt;decentralized platforms are increasingly trumpeted as an alternative&lt;/a&gt; to the current model. While these ideas are promising, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/the-decentralized-internet-is-here-with-some-glitches/&quot;&gt;I’m skeptical, especially after watching Silicon Valley&lt;/a&gt; (I know, I know!). This is because both radical transparency and privacy-first decentralization come with their own issues. The same systems that enable “openness” and/or “privacy” can also enable the inverse of their original intentions. Open source software has rising security concerns, especially after the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2014/6/19/18076318/heartbleed&quot;&gt;Heartbleed incident&lt;/a&gt;, where backdoors were built into a software and its subsequent updates. Telegram, which is a safe haven for privacy-advocates, is also a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/59nk3a/how-telegram-became-white-nationalists-go-to-messaging-platform&quot;&gt;central organizing platform for the alt-right movement&lt;/a&gt;. In an era of the Panama and Paradise papers – but also an era of protest photography, the role of privacy takes on enormously complex and differentiated roles depending on context. I’m not sure where I stand amongst these questions, let alone understand them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-why-am-i-still-writing-on-this-blog&quot;&gt;So why am I still writing on this blog?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I’m still not sure. All of these thoughts are very much underdeveloped. But in any case, I hope that these resources and writings can be useful to someone, if they ever end up stumbling upon this page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dear all,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Publication: Notes on the (American) Empire</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/field-notes/on-protests-revolutions-and-empire-notes-on-end/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Publication: Notes on the (American) Empire" /><published>2020-03-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-03-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/field-notes/on-protests-revolutions-and-empire-notes-on-end</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/field-notes/on-protests-revolutions-and-empire-notes-on-end/">&lt;p&gt;Dear all,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently published a piece for The Graduate Press, a student-run publication here at The Graduate Institute, titled “On Protests, Revolutions, and Empire: Notes on America”. This was for their Spring 2020 REVOLUTION issue. &lt;a href=&quot;https://thegraduatepress.files.wordpress.com/2020/03/tpg-publication-final.pdf&quot;&gt;You can download a copy of the issue here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dear all,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Impressions: On Mountains, Panels, and Fondue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/field-notes/geneva-first-field-notes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Impressions: On Mountains, Panels, and Fondue" /><published>2019-12-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-12-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/field-notes/geneva-first-field-notes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/field-notes/geneva-first-field-notes/">&lt;p&gt;Dear all,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a few months since I’ve arrived in Geneva. This is a fascinating place (though not without its challenges, of course), and I’m finally starting to feel settled. There’s a lot to share, and that will take time to process, but I wanted to post a few photos of the past few months. I’ve been getting lots of mountain time, overdosing on politics, and studying up on just about everything. More on that later; but in a meantime, a few photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A view from my flat:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582666518/room_with_a_view_gwikrm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;geneva&quot; title=&quot;geneva&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking back from the crag:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582666548/climbing_b0ljni.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Young climate protests at the Global Climate Strike, which happened to be on the same day as the Free Tibet protests:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582666597/climate_i1qw5n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582666654/tibet_lila7j.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Views of the Matterhorn:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582666677/mountain_j2kowj.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fondue at one of my favorite places in Geneva (Bains des Pâquis):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582666871/fondue_z5gj9f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many, many forums: on climate justice, on human-centred design, on Brazil’s politique, on jewel auctions, and everything in between…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582668184/auction_pyabm6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582666726/protest_1_j35xs4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582668298/todo_bien_fs4te1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, a photo of beautiful Lake Geneva at dusk:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/aleesteele/image/upload/v1582668146/lake_geneva_night_tecm6v.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure: I post more frequently on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/anneleesteele/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;; but will be returning to longform and this blog soon. I may be posting the cycling stories I’d compiled from last summer here as well, for posterity’s sake. Until soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dear all,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Greetings from Geneva– I’m bringing back the blog!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/field-notes/greetings-from-geneva-bringing-back-the-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Greetings from Geneva-- I'm bringing back the blog!" /><published>2019-09-18T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-09-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/field-notes/greetings-from-geneva-bringing-back-the-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/field-notes/greetings-from-geneva-bringing-back-the-blog/">&lt;p&gt;Dear all,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work and life has meant that I’ve been constantly on the move for the past few months (in all honesty- for the past few years is probably more realistic): somewhere between Kathmandu, Washington DC, and Bristol. It feels good to be living somewhere long(er) term, and I’m excited to be based in Geneva.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being stationary usually means that there’s time to reflect and digest. For the past few months, I’ve had the opportunity to go through arsenals of old photographs, writings, field notes and emails. While some of that has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/mmntsbyanne/&quot;&gt;posted here&lt;/a&gt;, I thought it might be nice to have my own space (as separate from a social network).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be a place to post thoughts, reflections, and adventures (both physical and intellectual). I hope that I’ll be able to back-post some old writings, specifically letters and photographs that were sent when I was more mobile than not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must admit: blogs have always felt a little weird for me. I mean, why would anyone be interested in anything I have to say? Why take the things that I fiercely protect as private thoughts, and put them into a public space? Especially a ‘public space’ like the internet, where I’m inevitably bound to get myself in trouble? Is it narcissism? Post-teenage angst? A combination of all of the above, perhaps?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to think that this place will be a bit more than that. First and foremost, I’d like this blog to be for those that were too far away to know what I was up to at the time, and well as for anyone that happens to be interested in what I’m up to these days. Perhaps more selfishly: this blog will also be for myself, a way of keeping myself accountable to writing, publishing, and digesting the world as my lens evolves. Finally, this is my small attempt at control over my digital half life, and over the parts of myself that are shared online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll inevitably make mistakes, but I might as well try. Let’s see what happens!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anne&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dear all,</summary></entry></feed>